Guide to the Durham Theatre Guild Records, 1946-1994
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Durham Theatre Guild records 1946-1994
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Durham Theatre Guild, 1947-1994.
12.0 Linear Feet 8500 Items
Community theatre of Durham County, North Carolina. Established in 1947 and disbanded in 1994.
The collection includes account books; tax and insurance records; board meeting minutes (dating from 1946-1994); scrapbooks and scrapbook files, arranged alphabetically (dating from 1950-1994); posters and handbills of the Durham Theatre Guild; audio and videocassettes; news clippings and photographs; and various ephemera, including buttons and t-shirts (dating from 1950-1993).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Durham Theatre Guild Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1995.
Historical Note
The Durham Theatre Guild was incorporated following a 1946 meeting of drama enthusiasts. Its first president was William N. Hardy, and the group produced multiple plays each year. It also sponsored drama programs in local high schools. The group disbanded in 1994.
Collection Overview
The collection includes account books; tax and insurance records; board meeting minutes (dating from 1946-1994); scrapbooks and scrapbook files, arranged alphabetically (dating from 1950-1994); posters and handbills of the Durham Theatre Guild; audio and videocassettes; news clippings and photographs; and various ephemera, including buttons and t-shirts (dating from 1950-1993).
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Durham Theatre Guild
Community theater -- North Carolina
Durham (N.C.) -- History
Contents of Collection
- Durham Theatre Guild Materials, 1946-1994, (12 boxes)
  - Records (Box 1)
  - Account books
  - T-shirts
  - Buttons, 1950-1993
  - Bylaws
  - Tax and insurance records
  - Videocassettes and audiocassettes
  - Board meeting minutes, 1946-1994 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook files, A-Z, 1950-1994 (Box 3-5)
  - Scrapbooks, 1950-1993 (Box 6-9)
  - News clippings
  - Photographs, etc.
  - Posters and handbills (Box 10-12)